Nikhil Singh

Phone: 9398514062

Email: Ns9440256@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Linkdin-nikhil

CAREER OBJECTIVES

Software Engineer with 2.5+ year's experience building and maintaining responsive websites in the technology and service industry. Highly skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery alongside modern frameworks and libraries. Interested about accessibility and usability of modern websites.

Work Experience and Projects					
2021-2022	AWS Mavericks, Fintech, Gaming Convention, Smart Manufacturing (Rock well)				
	Lead developer				
Summary	All the above are Microsite Designed and developed for Network18 group. The main theme of this				
	microsite was to allow the register and provide axis to live events respectively.				
Technicality The entire site is developed in PHP with UTM source tracking. For frontend validations and Ajax call for data transfer.					
2021-2022	Exide Batteries				
	Developer, Support				
Summary	Solar System Sizing Calculator is associated with Exide batteries. It gathers home appliance's data as input, and suggests the required battery, ups inverter load and estimated cost				
Technicality	ality It is a PWA Website developed using JavaScript, HTML, CSS and Ajax call for data transfer.				
2021-2022	Daimler and Jio (Money control, Network 18)				
	Development, support and Sanity				
Summary	Daimler created a CMS for dealer and clint management. Money Control and Network18 designed for Jio apps. Money control is based on stock market and Network18 is news app.				
Technicality	It is developed using React.js, Bootstrap3, CSS and jQuery.				

2021-2022 **BMW and SMOSS**

Development, BMW one app and SMOSS operation support.

Summary BMW manages its customers through OneApp – for android users and SMOSS manages all

Website related markets.

OneApp is developed in React Native and SMOSS operations are managed by using various Technicality

Tools like Grafana, Kubectl. The data base is managed by PGAdmin. To manage various

Campines, sales and finance CMS is used for both platforms.

SKILLS

TECHNICAL: JS, HTML, CSS, React JS, React Native, PHP, Python.

LANGUAGES: English, Hindi, Telugu.

Education

Graduated in Electronics and Communication.

Perceived Inter mediate with 88.6% and SSC with 84%.

HOBBIES

- Cricket
- Cycling

WORKSHOPS

• Attended Workshop on "AMAZON WEB SERVICES TECHNICAL ESSENTIALS" organized by APSSDC.

CERTIFICATIONS

- "SQL", by Hacker Rank.
- "CLOUD COMPUTING BASICS (CLOUD 101)", by Learn Ques.

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Thank you (NIKHIL SINGH.R)

Place: Hyderabad